EHSAN BASHIR

Product Owner

Karachi · +92 321 210 9730

brilliantahsan@gmail.com · http://linkedin.com/in/ehsanbashir

A Product Owner with a rare combination of strong technical development background and many years of experience in various business domains, managing client relationships and distributed development teams. Proven record of success over 5+ years leading agile software development teams and in developing data-rich B2B/B2C SaaS applications.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

TECHNICAL PROJECT MANAGER, MAK GLOBAL PAYMENT SOLUTIONS, KARACHI

Consistently identified and analyzed product risks, employing them as guiding principles for shaping future development strategies.

Adroitly led the development and launch of a new system, navigating complexities and achieving objectives within projected timelines and budgetary limits.

Empowered a team of 10+ engineers and analysts to achieve their full potential through personalized coaching and support.

Analyzed the company's current state and identified areas for improvement.

Collaborated with others to devise strategies for implementing the company vision.

Analyze feedback to determine customer needs and develop solutions.

Communicated regularly on project progress and status to the management.

Tracked and analyzed metrics to measure product success.

Developed Automate processes.

Revamped system functionality by implementing process-driven change management, ensuring smooth transitions and minimizing disruption.

AUGUST 2019 - AUGUST 2020

PRODUCT OWNER, IGNITE SOLUTIONS PET, RIYADH

Translated features into user stories within product backlog, refining and reprioritizing to reflect feature requirements.

Communicated the product vision and user stories into a language that the Scrum team could understand.

Worked with Scrum teams to ensure that user story acceptance criteria were clear, measurable, and achievable.

Effectively negotiated sprint goals with the Scrum team.

Bridge the gap between stakeholder and developers to meet product requirements.

Worked productively with product team and internal stakeholders to understand product requirements and business specifications.

Tracked and analyzed metrics to measure product success.

Planned and estimated 2-week sprints in a realistic yet time-efficient manner that allowed the teams to maximize their input and deliver according to the company roadmap.

Conducted scrum ceremonies (Sprint Planning, Sprint Review, Retrospective, Backlog Refinement).

Involved in multiple projects and handling teams that develop and support the UI and Back-end processes.

MARCH 2016 – JULY 2020

SCRUM MASTER, BRIGHTENINGTECH, RIYADH

Lead scrum teams consisting of 20+ members to streamline deliverables.

Helped product owner to prioritized product backlog and sprint backlog.

Conduct daily stand-ups.

Ensured user stories were ordered, defined and ready to be worked on by team.

Implemented agile mindset by conducting burn-down chart, team velocity analyses, and continuous improvement initiatives.

Removed obstacle for the team by escalating an issue to leadership resulting in early delivery of customer issue solution. Customer provided positive feedback.

Improved team velocity by incorporating capacity planning into sprint planning sessions.

DECEMBER 2013 - MARCH 2016

TEAM LEAD, INFINITEBYTES, KARACHI

Managed team of 15+ developers and designers.

Managed technical staff by hiring, training, coaching and evaluating job performance.

Helped research, plan, design and implement a complete technology stack re-architecture which enabled us to introduce speed and scalability improvements

Conducted daily stand-ups. Determined the team capacity.

Removed obstacles

Interviewed potential new hires, created an assessment to grade interviewees.

Documentation of Technical Specifications and High Level Technical Design for the business requirements.

FEBURARY 2012 - NOVEMBER 2013

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, ZENSOFT (PVT) LTD, KARACHI

Developed new & modified existing forms reports on 6i 10g.

Worked on Payroll System / Sugar Cane Accounting & Procurement System / Resume Management System / Investment Management System / Provident Fund Management / Gratuity Fund

Management. Create new & modify existing forms reports functions procedure & packages.

Used the Oracle as database 9i and Developer 6i, 9i, 10g as front hand tool, making the desired form and reports according to the Project requirement.

Deployed Project on application server.

Developed complex programs and modifications to programs from specifications as assigned.

Created or maintained database triggers, packages, procedure and functions.

Documented programs and program modifications to programs assigned.

Followed systems standards and procedures as defined architecture.

Used packages, procedure and functions to obtaining better performance of form, and used views instead of tables to take more efficient reports.

Managed database backup & restoration.

Created database. Work with tools PL/SQL, TOAD, FORMS and REPORTS.

FEBURARY 2008 - FEBURARY 2012

ORACLE PROGRAMER & I.T COORDINATOR, AFROZE TEXTILE, KARACHI

Developed new & modified existing forms reports on 6i 10g.

Worked on Payroll System / Sugar Cane Accounting & Procurement System / Resume Management System / Investment Management System / Provident Fund Management / Gratuity Fund Management. Create new & modify existing forms reports functions procedure & packages. Used the Oracle as database 9i and Developer 6i, 9i, 10g as front hand tool, making the desired form and reports according to the Project requirement.

Deployed Project on application server.

Developed complex programs and modifications to programs from specifications as assigned.

Created or maintained database triggers, packages, procedure and functions.

Documented programs and program modifications to programs assigned.

Followed systems standards and procedures as defined architecture.

Used packages, procedure and functions to obtaining better performance of form, and used views instead of tables to take more efficient reports.

Managed database backup & restoration.

Created database. Work with tools PL/SQL, TOAD, FORMS and REPORTS.

EDUCATION

DECEMBER 2012
MASTER'S - MBA, DIHE

With 3.48 CGPA.

AUGUST 2008

BACHELOR'S, JINNHA GOVT. COLLEGE

2nd Division

DECEMBER 2008

CERTIFICATION - ORACLE DBA & DEVELOPER, ORASOFT

SKILLS

- Agile and Scrum
- FinTech
- Epic & Feature Design
- Product Backlog Grooming
- Cloud Computing
- Communication
- Adaptability
- Conflict resolution

- Leadership and Team Motivation
- User Stories
- Sprint & Release Planning
- Decision Maker
- System Architect
- Knowledge Seeker
- Digital Solutions
- Technical Understanding

- Product Backlog Management
- Azure DevOps
- Product Roadmap
- App Development
- Multivendor Architecture
- KPI's Development
- Extreme Programing(XP)
- Team development

PROJECTS

- Point of Sales (multi-vendor)
- Downtown (multi-vendor)
- QuickBooks (Integration)
- R-House
- Green Bill (E-Invoice Integration)
- KYU (Cloud based queue management system)
- Geidea (Payment Terminal integration)

- Ignite Connect (B2B, B2C)
- Zoho (Integration)
- The PAC
- SPNBX (fitness gym schedule management)
- TEH (Event management)
- STCPay (Wallet Integration)
- KANZ (Loyalty)

- SAP reporting System
- Fund management
- Yarn management system
- Accounting & costing system
- Advance Accounting System
- What3Words (Integration)
- Smart POS
- Ignite Insights
- Schedule Management System
- Kl0ck Time Management System

- Smart Fuel
- GO Connect
- Card Payment System
- Digital Menu
- 3alber (event management)
- Sugar cane management system
- HRM
- Warehouse/Store Inventory management
- Process Automation
- KDS/NDS Waiter Kiosk